### AMAN GOEL

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science & Engineering, University of Michigan

Basic
Information

5<sup>th</sup> Year Ph.D. Candidate (adviser: Prof. Karem Sakallah) Formal Methods & Automated Reasoning Group, CSE University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, USA  $amangoel@umich.edu +1 (734) 881-0674 \\ aman-goel.github.io$ 

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests include exploring reliability & security of complex systems, and developing automated reasoning algorithms for ensuring system correctness. I also have a developing interest in data structures & algorithms, programming languages, machine learning and web systems. My current work focuses on automatic verification of distributed systems.

#### EDUCATION

#### University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, USA

Aug 2016 - Present

Ph.D. student, Computer Science & Engineering Grade Point Average: 3.96/4

#### IIT Madras, India

July 2011 - May 2016

Silver Medalist

Bachelor of Technology, Electrical Engineering Master of Technology, Microelectronics & VLSI

- Grade Point Average: 9.23/10

- Minor: Industrial Engineering (GPA: 9.33/10)

#### RECENT RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### $\bigcirc$ Developer of AVR

Sep 2016 - Present

AVR is a tool for automatic verification of state-transition systems

- Successfully applied on hardware and software systems
- Uses SMT solvers to perform word-level formal verification
- Uses data abstraction for scaling unbounded property verification
- Won  $1^{st}$  place in the prestigious Hardware Model Checking Competition (HWMCC) 2020 7 x %, 1 x %, 1 x % medals

#### O Developer of *IC3PO*

Nov 2019 - Present

 $\ensuremath{\mathsf{IC3PO}}$  is a tool for automatic, push-button verification of distributed systems

- Performs automated correctness checking and bug-hunting for distributed systems
- Uses formal methods and symmetry to simplify and automate verification tasks
- Generates quantified inductive invariants with both universal and existential quantifiers

#### Contributor to Open-source Tools

Summer 2020 @ Menlo Park, CA

Yices 2 is a state-of-the-art SMT solver from SRI

- Worked with the CSL team and developed techniques for quantified SMT solving

#### Contributor to Commercial Tools

Summer 2019 @ Haifa, Israel

JasperGold is a state-of-the-art formal verification platform from Cadence

- Developed word-level verification engines for JasperGold
- Worked with Cadence SVG (systems verification group) and developed algorithms for automatically solving hard verification tasks

RECENT SERVICE Artifact evaluation committees (AEC)

2019 - Present

OSDI 2021, VMCAI 2021, OOPSLA 2020, CAV 2020

Skills

Good knowledge of C++, C, Python, Verilog, Shell scripting Working knowledge of MATLAB, Java, HTML, LLVM Good understanding of SAT / SMT solvers

# SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- On Symmetry and Quantification: A New Approach to Verify Distributed Protocols Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In NASA Formal Methods Symposium (NFM), 2021.
- AVR: Abstractly Verifying Reachability

  Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In International Conference on Tools and Algorithms for the Construction and Analysis of Systems (TACAS), 2020.
- L4: Incremental Inference of Inductive Invariants for Verification of Distributed Protocols Ma, Haojun, Aman Goel, Jean-Baptiste Jeannin, Manos Kapritsos, Baris Kasikci, and Karem A. Sakallah. In the 27th Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP), 2019.
- Ma, Haojun, Aman Goel, Jean-Baptiste Jeannin, Manos Kapritsos, Baris Kasikci, and Karem A. Sakallah. In the Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (*HotOS*), 2019.
- Model checking of Verilog RTL using IC3 with syntax-guided abstraction
  Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In NASA Formal Methods Symposium (NFM), 2019.
- Empirical evaluation of IC3-based model checking techniques on Verilog RTL designs
  Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In 2019 Design, Automation & Test in Europe Conference
  & Exhibition (DATE), 2019.
- iitRACE: A memory efficient engine for fast incremental timing analysis
  Peddawad, Chaitanya, Aman Goel, B. Dheeraj, and Nitin Chandrachoodan. In 2015 IE-EE/ACM International Conference on Computer-Aided Design (ICCAD), 2015.

## Honors & Awards

- Recipient of Rackham Predoctoral Fellowship 2020-21 for outstanding PhD research
- Best student research award in the hardware discipline in the CSE Graduate Student Honors Competition 2019 for outstanding PhD research
- Recipient of Dwight F. Benton fellowship at University of Michigan for 2016-17
- Recipient of research travel grant and Israel travel award for 2019
- Branch position 2 in Electrical Engineering at IIT Madras (Silver medalist)
- Won international  $3^{rd}$  place in TAU Contest at ICCAD 2015 for Incremental Timing Analysis
- Recipient of best undergraduate research project at Pan IIT Research Expo 2014
- Recipient of *Electronics for You* prize for best academic performance at graduate level
- Won National Award for the Empowerment of Persons with Disabilities 2013 for Solar Charger for Hearing Aid Devices
- Invited participant at Summer School on Formal Techniques 2018 hosted by SRI

Selected
Courses

$Advanced\ Algorithms$	$Advanced\ Compilers$	Formal Verification
$AI\ Foundations$	Data Structures & Alg.	Digital Systems Testing

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University of Michigan:

EECS 281 Data Structures & Algorithms	Aug - Dec 2017 & 2018
EECS 478 Logic Synthesis & Optimization	Jan - Apr 2018
EECS 579 Digital System Testing	Aug - Dec 2019
EECS 492 Introduction to Artificial Intelligence	Jan - Apr 2020
Madaga	

IIT Madras:

EE 5311 Digital IC Design

Aug - Nov 2015

EE 5332 Mapping Signal Processing Algorithms to DSP Architectures

Jan - May 2016

Hobbies

Swimming, Water Polo, Skating, Badminton, Soccer

Aman Goel 2 / 2